<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[yo, it's joe]]></title>
  <link href="http://thebroda.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thebroda.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-10T20:39:34-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://thebroda.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Joe Hermann]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://thebroda.github.io/blog/2014/06/10/an-update/"/>
    
    <updated>2014-06-10T20:34:27-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://thebroda.github.io/blog/2014/06/10/an-update</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What have I been up to?  Working, <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/9251989-joe">reading books</a>, cooking, <a href="http://chipotlecultivate.com/">attending corporate-ass festivals</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dolores_Park">chilling</a>, etc.  Oh, I also ate some <a href="http://lavasf.com/">dope ramen</a> yesterday.</p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week 1 in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://thebroda.github.io/blog/2014/05/27/week-1-in-review/"/>
    
    <updated>2014-05-27T20:24:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://thebroda.github.io/blog/2014/05/27/week-1-in-review</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had quite a bit of fun during my first week in the Bay.  <a href="http://www.saymedia.com/">Work</a> was chill, and it looks I&rsquo;m going to have some interesting coding challenges with <a href="https://angularjs.org/">AngularJS</a> this summer.  Enough about work!  Here&rsquo;s a quick summary of the my super touristy Memorial day weekend.</p>

<p>Saturday evening I took the Caltrain down to Stanford to party with the future roomie.  Good times were had.  The campus itself really blew me away.  The quality, scale, and consistency of the architecture is justification enough for any visit to their campus.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://i.imgur.com/s1FAq4n.jpg" width="377" height="631" title="Stanford" ></p>

<p>I spent Sunday morning exploring a little more of Stanford&rsquo;s truly serene campus.  After I got home, I went out to eat with my cousin Tracy and her fiancé JP.  Sadly, I didn&rsquo;t snap any pictures, but I did eat some <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/papito-west-san-francisco-3">delicious tacos</a> and tried <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/smitten-ice-cream-san-francisco-3">Smitten Ice Cream</a>  over in Hayes Valley (pro-tip: try the Strawberry Balsamic flavor).</p>

<p>After sleeping in on Monday, I woke up and bought a bike.  I bought a single-speed because it was cheap.  I biked from Fisherman&rsquo;s wharf to, but not across, the Golden Gate Bridge.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://i.imgur.com/3yusxM9.jpg" width="320" height="534" title="Golden Gate Bridge Selfie" ></p>

<p>As I biked from the bridge back to my place in NoPa I realized a few things:</p>

<ol>
<li>San Francisco&rsquo;s hills are no joke.</li>
<li>I am out of shape.</li>
<li>A single-speed bike is no way to bike these hills for someone who is it out of shape.</li>
</ol>


<p>As a result of this embarassingly strenuous effort, I ordered some pretty good pizza from <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/little-star-pizza-san-francisco">Little Star Pizza</a>.  Based on the yelp reviews, I think it might be a little overrated&hellip; but that didn&rsquo;t stop me from immediately eating half of it.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://i.imgur.com/hNxbxBV.jpg" width="406" height="542" title="Pizza" ></p>

<p>It was a nice introductory weekend to the city, and it&rsquo;s shaping up to be a fun summer.</p>

<h3>DOPE FIND OF THE WEEK</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/oasis-cafe-san-francisco-3">The café</a> kitty corner from me serves Ethiopian food.  <em>Mmmmmmmm</em>, Sambusa!</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://i.imgur.com/oVCMdPN.jpg" title="Sambusa" ></p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consumerist Trip To J Town]]></title>
    <link href="http://thebroda.github.io/blog/2014/05/18/consumerist-trip-to-j-town/"/>
    
    <updated>2014-05-18T20:57:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://thebroda.github.io/blog/2014/05/18/consumerist-trip-to-j-town</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Admittedly, I didn&rsquo;t do anything interesting today.  I woke up and explored a little more of the NoPa area, expanding my knowledge of my immediate surroundings.  The Victorian architecture and rolling hills hold a strong allure after so many years spent in the Midwest.  As I mentioned in the previous post, today was the Bay to Breakers run.  The alcohol was flowing and there were countless people dressed in crazy costumes (à la Mardi Gras).</p>

<p><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=Geary+Blvd+%26+Webster+St,+San+Francisco,+CA&amp;hl=en&amp;sll=37.784707,-122.431104&amp;sspn=0.009717,0.021136&amp;oq=Geary+Blvd+%26+WEb,+San+Francisco,+CA&amp;hnear=Geary+Blvd+%26+Webster+St,+San+Francisco,+California&amp;t=m&amp;z=16&amp;layer=c&amp;cbll=37.784666,-122.431113&amp;panoid=WW0yILJrxrb1v4lABaOESA&amp;cbp=13,73.46,,0,9.41"><img class="center" src="http://i.imgur.com/QuKuFlD.jpg" width="489" height="652" title="Japantown" ></a></p>

<p>Later, I went to the Japantown Mall and bought <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/daiso-japan-san-francisco-3">cheap plastic goods</a> to help organize my room.  I topped off this trip by eating some subpar Wonton soup in the mall food court.  I wasted away the rest of the day, but I&rsquo;m excited to start work tomorrow and see what challenges the summer has in store.</p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just Touched Down]]></title>
    <link href="http://thebroda.github.io/blog/2014/05/17/just-touched-down/"/>
    
    <updated>2014-05-17T23:14:54-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://thebroda.github.io/blog/2014/05/17/just-touched-down</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I touched down at the San Francisco International Airport at around 6 PM PST.  My summer in the Bay has begun.  After a far too expensive taxi ride, I picked up the keys to my place in NoPa.  The neighborhood seems really active and there are a ton of things to do within walking distance.  My landlord happens to own a party store less than a block from my doorstep, so the big win of today (besides getting here) is the revelation of accesible, discounted microbrews.  I&rsquo;m also less than a 5 minute walk from Alamo Square park, so I was obliged to take a picture of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Painted_ladies">Painted ladies</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=painted+ladies,+San+Francisco,+CA&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=37.776295,-122.432778&amp;spn=0.009718,0.021136&amp;sll=37.784666,-122.431113&amp;sspn=0.009785,0.021136&amp;t=m&amp;z=16&amp;iwloc=A"><img class="center" src="http://i.imgur.com/xlhL1yd.jpg" title="Painted ladies" ></a></p>

<p>As you can see, some of these fine ladies are currently under construction.  After this brief walking tour of the immediate area, I lazily called it a day&hellip; but not before grabbing a chicken burrito from the conveniently located <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/el-rancho-grande-san-francisco">El Rancho Grande</a>.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://i.imgur.com/2E2xDtb.jpg" width="400" height="534" title="Burrito" ></p>

<p>Yummy, reasonably priced Mexican food?  It&rsquo;s safe to say I&rsquo;ll be back.  <a href="http://www.baytobreakers.com/">Bay to Breakers</a> will have runners come through the area tomorrow, so it should be party around these parts.</p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review of The Autobiography of Malcolm X]]></title>
    <link href="http://thebroda.github.io/blog/2014/05/13/review-of-the-autobiography-of-malcolm-x/"/>
    
    <updated>2014-05-13T21:18:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://thebroda.github.io/blog/2014/05/13/review-of-the-autobiography-of-malcolm-x</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Autobiography_of_Malcolm_X"><em>The Autobiography of Malcolm X</em></a>, coauthored with Alex Haley from their collaborative sessions between 1963 and Malcolm X&rsquo;s death in 1965.  In a move that you will likely often see from this blog, I am reposting the review that I made on <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/9251989-joe">my Goodreads account</a>.  This book was immensely interesting for both the well-crafted narrative and the important questions it asks.  As a follow-up to the ideas in this book, I&rsquo;ll also be adding <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Making-Malcolm-The-Myth-Meaning/dp/0195102851">Making Malcolm</a> by Michael Eric Dyson to my reading list, his critique of Haley&rsquo;s myth-making promises a VERY worthy read.  This text definitely establishes the mythos of Malcolm X that has been cultivated (marketed) since his death.  My review follows.</p>

<h3>Review of <em>The Autobiography of Malcolm X</em></h3>

<p>Why am I giving this book 5 stars?  Is it because Malcolm X presents a flawless philosophy?  Because he presents a well-rounded solution to America&rsquo;s racial problems?  No.  He even admitted at the end of his life that he was confused on the exact nature of his political direction.  In the epilogue, Haley notes that:</p>

<blockquote><p> On Thursday he told a reporter, in an interview which did not appear until after his death: &ldquo;I&rsquo;m man enough to tell you that I can&rsquo;t put my finger on exactly what my philosophy is now, but I&rsquo;m flexible.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p><img class="right" src="http://i.imgur.com/DTSc1Nv.jpg" width="167" height="280" title="The Autobiography of Malcolm X" ></p>

<p>So is my rating of 5 stars simply the result of Malcolm X&rsquo;s historical significance?  Again, the answer is no.  I&rsquo;m not going to spend the time necessary to critique his original &ldquo;white devil&rdquo; argument (an argument he later realized was flawed), I&rsquo;m not going argue against the religious nature of his doctrine, nor do I wish to dwell on his sexism and failure to recognize the extent of non-racial forms of oppression.  All these criticisms are valid, and should be explored by anyone who wishes to engage these topics seriously.  The fact is that despite his shortcomings, Malcolm X was a shrewd observer of the Black American condition.  Though he clearly isn&rsquo;t a Marxist, his analysis of America&rsquo;s &ldquo;race problem&rdquo; contains materialist undertones that highlight the subtleties of systematic oppression and the results of such oppression. Though his solutions may have been misguided, Malcolm X&rsquo;s critical analysis demonstrates the depth of his thinking.  His desire to question, to understand, and to grow made Malcolm X an admirable political leader, and  his passion probably would have lead him to affect great change had his life not been cut short.  It would have been interesting to see him develop and round out his own philosophy, to develop solutions outside the limited framework created by Elijah Muhammad and Nation of Islam.  His analysis of American society forces readers to question ones values, analyze our collective history, and compare the merit of various solutions to systematic oppression.</p>

<p>His analysis and controversy makes the text politically valuable, but the main reason this is 5 stars is the narrative.  Alex Haley weaves the life of Malcolm X into a cohesive and superb <i>story</i>.  This book is exciting from start to finish. <em>The Autobiography of Malcolm X</em> is an origin story, but an origin story without resolution.  One sees not only how Malcolm X came to be, but how he came to doubt who he was.  This vulnerability should resonate with all of us.  We will never see Malcolm X resolve his doubts, never see how he would have answered the toughest questions we face.  That is a tragedy America must share.</p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Obligatory First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://thebroda.github.io/blog/2014/05/11/first-post/"/>
    
    <updated>2014-05-11T17:10:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://thebroda.github.io/blog/2014/05/11/first-post</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just set up this blog via Octopress.  So it begins.  I&rsquo;ll be using this to catalog my adventures, projects, and thoughts.  Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>