<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: books, | yo, it's joe]]></title>
  <link href="http://joehermann.com/blog/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://joehermann.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-08T13:05:45-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://joehermann.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Joe Hermann]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review of The Autobiography of Malcolm X]]></title>
    <link href="http://joehermann.com/blog/2014/05/14/review-of-the-autobiography-of-malcolm-x/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-14T00:18:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://joehermann.com/blog/2014/05/14/review-of-the-autobiography-of-malcolm-x</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Autobiography_of_Malcolm_X"><em>The Autobiography of Malcolm X</em></a>, coauthored with Alex Haley from their collaborative sessions between 1963 and Malcolm X&rsquo;s death in 1965.  In a move that you will likely often see from this blog, I am reposting the review that I made on <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/9251989-joe">my Goodreads account</a>.  This book was immensely interesting for both the well-crafted narrative and the important questions it asks.  As a follow-up to the ideas in this book, I&rsquo;ll also be adding <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Making-Malcolm-The-Myth-Meaning/dp/0195102851">Making Malcolm</a> by Michael Eric Dyson to my reading list, his critique of Haley&rsquo;s myth-making promises a VERY worthy read.  This text definitely establishes the mythos of Malcolm X that has been cultivated (marketed) since his death.  My review follows.</p>

<h3>Review of <em>The Autobiography of Malcolm X</em></h3>

<p>Why am I giving this book 5 stars?  Is it because Malcolm X presents a flawless philosophy?  Because he presents a well-rounded solution to America&rsquo;s racial problems?  No.  He even admitted at the end of his life that he was confused on the exact nature of his political direction.  In the epilogue, Haley notes that:</p>

<blockquote><p> On Thursday he told a reporter, in an interview which did not appear until after his death: &ldquo;I&rsquo;m man enough to tell you that I can&rsquo;t put my finger on exactly what my philosophy is now, but I&rsquo;m flexible.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p><img class="right <a" src="href="http://i.imgur.com/DTSc1Nv.jpg">http://i.imgur.com/DTSc1Nv.jpg</a>" width="167" height="280" title="The Autobiography of Malcolm X" ></p>

<p>So is my rating of 5 stars simply the result of Malcolm X&rsquo;s historical significance?  Again, the answer is no.  I&rsquo;m not going to spend the time necessary to critique his original &ldquo;white devil&rdquo; argument (an argument he later realized was flawed), I&rsquo;m not going argue against the religious nature of his doctrine, nor do I wish to dwell on his sexism and failure to recognize the extent of non-racial forms of oppression.  All these criticisms are valid, and should be explored by anyone who wishes to engage these topics seriously.  The fact is that despite his shortcomings, Malcolm X was a shrewd observer of the Black American condition.  Though he clearly isn&rsquo;t a Marxist, his analysis of America&rsquo;s &ldquo;race problem&rdquo; contains materialist undertones that highlight the subtleties of systematic oppression and the results of such oppression. Though his solutions may have been misguided, Malcolm X&rsquo;s critical analysis demonstrates the depth of his thinking.  His desire to question, to understand, and to grow made Malcolm X an admirable political leader, and  his passion probably would have lead him to affect great change had his life not been cut short.  It would have been interesting to see him develop and round out his own philosophy, to develop solutions outside the limited framework created by Elijah Muhammad and Nation of Islam.  His analysis of American society forces readers to question ones values, analyze our collective history, and compare the merit of various solutions to systematic oppression.</p>

<p>His analysis and controversy makes the text politically valuable, but the main reason this is 5 stars is the narrative.  Alex Haley weaves the life of Malcolm X into a cohesive and superb <i>story</i>.  This book is exciting from start to finish. <em>The Autobiography of Malcolm X</em> is an origin story, but an origin story without resolution.  One sees not only how Malcolm X came to be, but how he came to doubt who he was.  This vulnerability should resonate with all of us.  We will never see Malcolm X resolve his doubts, never see how he would have answered the toughest questions we face.  That is a tragedy America must share.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
